Finding Aid for the Raymond Chandler Papers, 1930-1959
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Writings By and About Raymond Chandler
  - Published
    - Raymond Chandler speaking. v.p., 1959 (Box 9-12)
      - Manuscripts. n.p. and New York., 1960 (Box 10-12)
        - Copies of Raymond Chandler letters. n.p., (60 items: ca. 70 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon).; Item count approximate.. (Box 11, Folder 2)
          Houghton Mifflin correspondence.
          Folder 5 of 8.
        - Copies of Raymond Chandler letters. n.p., (45 items: ca. 50 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon).; Item count approximate.. (Box 11, Folder 3)
          Hamish Hamilton correspondence.
          Folder 6 of 8.
        - Copies of Raymond Chandler letters. n.p., (40 items: ca. 50 leaves, typescript carbon and photostatic copies).; Item count approximate.. (Box 11, Folder 4)
          Chandler / Charles Morton / Atlantic Monthly correspondence.
          Folder 7 of 8.
        - Copies of Raymond Chandler letters. n.p., (100 items: ca. 150 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon).; Item count approximate.. (Box 11, Folder 5)
          Folder 8 of 8.
        - Page proofs and “Chandlerisms.” n.p., 1962; (2 items: 264pp. and 1 leaf, typescript). (Box 11, Folder 6)
        - Title page-p.259. n.p., 1960; (Typescript). (Box 11, Folder 7)
          With note “Finish script.”
        - pp.260-450. n.p., 1960; (Typescript). (Box 11, Folder 8)
        - Appendix. n.p., 1960; (5 items: ca. 90 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon). (Box 12, Folder 1)
          With 4 notes from Dorothy Gardiner.
        - Excerpts with subject notes attached. n.p., 1960; (26 items: ca. 125 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon). (Box 12, Folder 2)
        - Copies of Raymond Chandler letters. n.p., (2 items: 17 leaves, 1 leaf, typescript and typescript carbon). (Box 12, Folder 3)
          Group of letters borrowed by Philip Durham with letter of transmittal returning them, 1966.
      - Research material. v.p. and La Jolla., March 26, 1957 (Box 9, 12)
        - Letters between Raymond Chandler and William Campbell Gault., 1954 (circa) 1958; (12 items: 11 letters and 1 original letter - typed transcripts and typescript signed). (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - Letter from Raymond Chandler to Mr. Howard., March 26, 1957; (4 leaves [4pp.], photostatic copy of typescript signed). (Box 9, Folder 14)
        - Letter from Raymond Chandler to Edgar N. Carter, and letter of transmittal from Philip Durham to Edgard N. Carter returning the original letter., June 3, 1956; (4 items: 2 leaves, 2 leaves, 2 leaves, 1 leaf - typescript signed [2 copies] - typescript, typescript carbon, 2 photostatic copies and typed transcript). (Box 9, Folder 15)
        - Raymond Chandler - Robert Campigny Correspondence. London., April 19, 1958; (3 items: each 1 leaf, typescript carbon, typescript and typescript carbon). (Box 9, Folder 16)
          Letter from Raymond Chandler to Robert Campigny. Carbon of Raymond Chandler's reply in French, on the back of Ritz Hotel writing paper.
          With 2 transcripts in English.
        - Letters to Wilbur Jordan Smith, UCLA. v.p., v.d.; (5 items: 1 leaf, 1 leaf, 2 leaves, 1 leaf, 1 leaf - typescript signed, photstatic copies and duplicate copies of letters). (Box 12, Folder 4)
          Copy of October 16, 1958 letter has notes by Dorothy Gardiner.
    - Reviews, essays, advertisements, etc. re Publication. v.p., v.d.; (Various clippings and photostatic copies). (Box 12, Folder 7-9, Box 14, Folder 4)
      - 14 items. (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - 16 items. (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - 7 items. (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - 5 items. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Articles about Raymond Chandler, including obituaries - Biographical. v.p., v.d.; (6 items, Various, clippings). (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Down These Mean Streets by Philip Durham - Research material. La Plata, Missouri., October 27, 1958; (2 items: each 3 leaves, typescript signed, photostatic copy). (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Letter from Lester Dent to Durham. Letter re Cap Shaw and Black Mask.
    - Down these mean streets by Philip Durham - Research material. v.p., 1960; (4 items, 1 leaf, 1 leaf, 1 leaf, 4 leaves - typescript signed, holograph, typescript). (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Letters and transcripts.
      Includes 3 notes and letters, and transcripts of Chandler letters and article.
- Writings About Raymond Chandler
  - BBC Production
    - Raymond Chandler speaking - Production material. London., 1962 (Box 12, Folder 15-25)
      - Letters from Helga Greene to Julian Symons. London, (Letters dated April 12 and June 18)., (2 items: 1 leaf, 1 leaf, typescript signed). (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Letter from Hamish Hamilton to Julian Symons. London., May 2, 1962; (Typescript signed). (Box 12, Folder 16)
        Ex libris Julian Symons.
        Dealer purchase[?].
      - Radio broadcast by Julian Symons. London., 1962; (13 leaves, mimeograph, typescript with corrections). (Box 12, Folder 17)
        Broadcast July 4, 1962
      - Letter from J.B. Priestley to Julian Symons. Starford., April 13, 1962; (Typescript signed). (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Letter from Robert Popock to Julian Symons. London, June 6, 1962., (Typescript signed). (Box 12, Folder 19)
        Letter is signed “Brenda,” secretary to Robert Popock.
      - Raymond Chandler speaking by Julian Symons. n.p., circa 1962; (5 leaves, holograph). (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Raymond Chandler by J.B. Priestley. n.p., circa 1962; (2 leaves, mimeograph). (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Raymond Chandler by F.J. Francis. n.p., circa 1962; (4 leaves, mimeograph). (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - [Raymond Chandler] by Frank Norman. n.p., May 31, 1962; (3 leaves, mimeograph). (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - Extract of interview between Ian Fleming and Raymond Chandler. n.p., (1 leaf, mimeograph). (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - Raymond Chandler by Michael Gilbert. n.p., May 16, 1962; (7 leaves, mimeograph). (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Australian Production
    - Who is Raymond Chandler - Production material. n.p., June 30, 1975; (12 leaves, mimeograph). (Box 12, Folder 26)
      Australian radio broadcast.